usagold.com 2019-06-26

# USAGOLD Privacy Policy

**USAGOLD Privacy Policy**

USAGOLD (the “Firm”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our Terms of Use, Risk Disclosure, and Online Shipping Policy) is presented to you in order to help you make an informed decision about using this website and to explain to you what information we collect, how we store that information, and how we may use it. By using USAGold (the “Website[s]”), you are consenting to this Privacy Policy and to have your personal data transferred to and/or processed in the United States in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.  **The Firm does not rent, share, sell, or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.   **The data collection practices set out in this Privacy Policy are for the primary purpose of fulfilling your orders and providing customer support. Please do not use the Website or purchase any products over the phone if you do not agree with this policy and any other policies listed on the Website.

**Information We Collect**

1\. Non-Personally Identifiable Information

When you enter the Website, we may collect certain non-personally identifiable information. This may include your browser information (including browser type, browser version, host operating system, and browser language) and your IP address. The Firm uses this information to help diagnose problems with our server and for other administrative purposes including, but not limited to, directing you to a geographically closer data center and providing you with content and services in your country's local language and currency. 

In addition, aggregate traffic information may also be collected at the Website from this non-personally identifiable information.  We may use this data for improving the services offered on the Website. The Firm, however, does not share or sell any aggregate information collected for marketing purposes.

2\. Personally Identifiable Information

Many of the services offered on the Website are only made available if we have certain information about you.  To access these services, you will, from time to time, be asked to submit personal information about yourself.  We may collect and process the following personal information related to our services:

> _Registration information_.  In registering for the Website, we require certain contact information including your name, e-mail address, and phone number. 
> 
> _Information to fulfill your order_.  When placing an order online at the Website or over the phone with our customer service team, we collect your name, phone number, address, and personal payment information. 
> 
> _Support_. If you contact us, we maykeep a record of that correspondence and record conversations for training and/or monitoring purposes.
> 
> _Payment card or financial account information._   We may collect payment card or financial account information to the extent necessary to execute transactions requested by you.
> 
> _Social security number._ We may collect your social security number in connection with your sale of coins or bullion to the Firm if we determine that we are specifically required by applicable regulations to report this sale to the Internal Revenue Service.

3\. Use of Cookies

The Firm uses cookies on the Website.  By using the Website you accept the use of cookies in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If you do not accept the use of these cookies please disable them following the instructions in this Privacy Policy. 

What is a cookie?

Cookies are small text files that websites place in your browser when you visit them. When you return to the site, the site can access its previously placed cookie to uniquely identify your browser. Cookies accomplish several different things. They recall your preferences at a website, help content render more efficiently, and improve the overall user experience on a website. They can also help advertisers see what interests you and what advertising may be relevant to you.  For further information on cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. 

What types of cookies do we use on the Website?

We use two different types of cookies on this website: (1) Strictly Necessary Cookies, and (2) Analytics Cookies.

_Strictly Necessary Cookies_ : These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as accessing secure areas of the website. These cookies do not gather information about you that could be used for marketing or remembering where you have been on the internet. 

_Analytics Cookies_ : These cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance, which pages visitors go to most often, and if they get error messages from web pages.  These cookies do not collect information that identifies you. All the information that these cookies collect is anonymous and is used only to improve how a website works.

Specifically, the Firm uses Google Analytics Cookies on the Website.  Information collected by the Google Analytics cookies will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States of America in accordance with its privacy practices. To see an overview of privacy at Google and how this applies to Google Analytics, visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/#toc-analytics>. You may opt out of tracking by Google Analytics by visiting <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB>. 

You can enable, disable or delete analytics cookies within your browser. In order to do this, follow the instructions provided by your browser (usually located within the “Help”, “Tools” or “Edit” menu).  Disabling a cookie or category of cookie does not delete the cookie from your browser; you will need to do this yourself from within your browser by choosing the option to delete cookies.  If you have disabled one or more analytics cookies, we may still use information collected from cookies prior to your disabled preference being set, however, we will stop using the disabled cookie to collect any further information. 

4\. Privacy of Children and Sensitive Consumer Information

The Firm does not knowingly collect information from anyone under the age of 18.

"Except to the extent that we may collect financial account information, payment card information or social security numbers as provided in this policy, the Firm does not knowingly obtain or store Sensitive Consumer Information, such as insurance plan numbers; information that describes the precise real-time geographic location of an individual; or precise information related to health or medical conditions."

If the Firm is made aware that we have received information from anyone under the age of 18 or Sensitive Consumer Information in violation of this Privacy Policy, we will use reasonable efforts to locate and remove that information from our records.

**B. Use of Information Collected**

1\. Primary Purpose of Information Collected

The information and data collected by the Website is primarily for the purposes of:

Processing your orders effectively;

Ensuring that content from our site is presented to you in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;

Notifying you about changes to our service and policies;

Responding to your customer support inquiries; and,

Complying with government reporting obligations. 

2\. Mailings

The Website may periodically contact you using information supplied to the site.  You may opt out of receiving certain communications, such as newsletters or other emails, by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of such emailsa.

**C. Disclosure of your Personal Information**

1\. Third Parties

We do not rent, share, sell, or trade personally identifiable information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

2\. Compliance with Law

The Firm reserves the right to disclose your personal information, without prior notice to you, as required by law or when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our web site.  Furthermore, we may share your personal information when we believe it is necessary to protect our interests or our property, to prevent fraud or other illegal activity perpetrated through the Website or using the Firm’s name, or to prevent imminent bodily harm.  This may include, but is not limited to, sharing information with other companies, lawyers, agents or government agencies. 

3\. Service Providers

The Firm may employ service providers and other companies and individuals to perform functions and provide services on our behalf (e.g. credit card processing, shipping, insurance).  These entities may have access to your personal information to the extent needed to perform their functions and also to provide you with the services that you have requested, but these service providers shall be contractually obligated not use this information for any other purpose. 

**D. Security**

We have implemented reasonable measures to protect the information we collect and store, taking into consideration the types of risks we face and the reasonable protections available to us. No method protecting information is 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**E. Privacy Practices of Third Parties**

When you click on links or advertising, third parties may place their own cookies or other technological devices on your Internet browser, independent of the Website.  We have no control over these third parties and no responsibility for the technologies they employ.  To learn how a particular web site collects and uses your information, you should read the privacy policy of that website.

**F. Changes to Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently and at least each time you submit personal information to the Website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here at this privacy page, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage. The date of the most recent revisions will also appear on this page. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your interactions with the Firm.

**G.** **Questions**

For questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy please contact:

Jen Hyde  
1-800-869-5115  
marketing@usagold.com 

Last Updated: 9/24/2013
